<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Nodes&amp;Edges - Pierre&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://pwuethri.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nodes&amp;Edges - Pierre&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://pwuethri.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://pwuethri.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pwuethri.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remapping the Caps lock key to Ctrl</title>
      <link>https://pwuethri.github.io/posts/220518_remapping_caps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pwuethri.github.io/posts/220518_remapping_caps/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I don&amp;rsquo;t find myself using the Caps lock key that much and would rather have it mapped to Control for convienience. While this is really straight-forward on a Mac, it requires a non-obvious solution on Windows. Luckily, SO came to the rescue.
The Recipe We need to run Powershell as an administrator and type the following commands:
$hexified = &amp;#34;00,00,00,00,00,00,00,00,02,00,00,00,1d,00,3a,00,00,00,00,00&amp;#34;.Split(&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;) | % { &amp;#34;0x$_&amp;#34;}; $kbLayout = &amp;#39;HKLM:\System\CurrentControlSet\Control\Keyboard Layout&amp;#39;; New-ItemProperty -Path $kbLayout -Name &amp;#34;Scancode Map&amp;#34; -PropertyType Binary -Value ([byte[]]$hexified); After reboot, the caps lock key will be mapped to Ctrl</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install WSL on Windows</title>
      <link>https://pwuethri.github.io/posts/220517_installing_wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pwuethri.github.io/posts/220517_installing_wsl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Windows Subsystem Linux (WSL) is an amazing feature that allows users to run full Linux distros directly from Windows. It removes the need to run a virtual machine or restart and select an OS during dualbooting.
In this post, we will see how easy it is to install WSL on Windows and get an Ubuntu distribution up and running.
Installing WSL Installing WSL can be done by running Powershell (as an administrator) and run the command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Coding Environment - Part 1: Getting Started with VIM</title>
      <link>https://pwuethri.github.io/posts/220513_getting_started_with_vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pwuethri.github.io/posts/220513_getting_started_with_vim/</guid>
      <description>Source: xkcd Comic
Introduction Current or aspiring Engineer/Scientist are very likely to end up in a situation where coding will be required. I coded nearly every day in my jobs so far and it is therefore worthwhile to spend some time on finding and configuring available tools to ensure a smooth and productive experience.
My goal for this series is to describe how to set up a functioning coding environment on MacOS (Linux distros will be very similar if not the same).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello there!</title>
      <link>https://pwuethri.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pwuethri.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my personal blog, my name is Pierre Wüthrich.
I am a Machine Learning Engineer / Data Scientist passionate about topics ranging from AI to Quantum Computing.
This webpage hosted on GitHub is my personal notes repository where I will occasionally make posts with interesting tidbits of coding/consulting I learned on my professional journey.
Contact Information Please feel free to contact me to discuss AI in general or just to say hello :-) You can find my SNS info on the landing page!</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
